Hey everyone, and thanks for jumping
back into the cryptoverse.
Today, we're going to talk about
Bitcoin, and we're going to be providing
an update to the bear market resistance
band. If you guys like the content, make
sure you subscribe to the channel, give
the video a thumbs up, and also check
out the sale on Into the Cryptoverse
Premium at intothecryptoverse.com.
As a reminder,
we are having the first
ITC conference, Investing Through the
Cycles. We're getting a lot of a lot of
great speakers. We have some more lined
up that we're going to be announcing on
the coming week. So, looking forward to
seeing
you guys at at the conference. Let's go
ahead and jump in. So, so Bitcoin's
trading between 64 and 65K. Now, I've
not made a video in over a week. Now,
there have been a lot of videos released
this past week, but I was out of town.
They were all pre-recorded. But, in
reality, not a lot happened this week.
The Bitcoin opened the week up at 64.7K,
and as I make this video,
it's basically at 64.7K.
We went all the way up to around 67K.
We've gone as low as 63.7.
Um
but not a lot not a whole lot has
happened.
But, what has happened over the last few
weeks is what always
maybe not always, but what tends to
happen in July of midterm years.
And that is
a rally back up.
If you look at
the monthly returns for Bitcoin in
midterm years in July, you can see that
in 2022, up 20%. In 2018, up almost 40%.
So far, we're up about 10. Now, the
issue is that in both 2022
and 2018, and also in 2014, August and
September were red, right? They were red
months.
Now, in 2018,
if you look at at 2018, which is I feel
like the best comparison in terms of
market structure, not necessarily in
terms of understanding liquidity and
flows and that sort of stuff, that's
more like 2019 ask, but in terms of
market structure, it's like 2018, where
you have a February low,
you then set a higher low in late March,
early April, you sweep the low in late
June, early July, and then you go back
up to that bear market resistance band
by late July or early August. This the
playbook has been the same. Your low in
February, your higher low in late March,
early April, you sweep the low in late
June, early July, and then you rally
back on up near that bear market
resistance band.
Now, what's interesting is that every
we've followed this basically every
month for the entire year and every
single time, you know, I know the sort
of the desire is say well, this time is
going to be different, but it just keeps
not being different, you know? I mean,
like I I've been there before where I
want to overcomplicate stuff, but this
is the reality is just been it's been
the same. And when you look at the
year-to-date ROI of Bitcoin in 2026 and
compare it to 2018, the lows kind of
line up, right? You have your February
low, your your um
your sort of higher low in late March,
early April, your lower low in June,
late June, early July, even the
countertrend rally is sort of time
lining up relatively well and you can
see that the rally lasted up into July
and then we came back down.
And so, what I'm guessing
as to how this will play out is that
Bitcoin will likely get rejected around
that area, just like it did in 2018, and
then come back down in sort of the
August to September time frame. And
remember, historically, it's Q4
where you kind of
reset all the on-chain indicators,
right? It's the fourth quarter of the
year. So,
the nice thing about what's happening
now is that while it feels very
different from prior cycles, it's
actually more or less the same. It's not
really that different. The main reason
it feels different again is because we
topped on apathy rather than euphoria,
but you just look at the year-to-date
RLI from a structural perspective,
it's the same.
The only difference is that the the the
level at which we dropped from wasn't as
high. For this to feel more like 2018,
it would have required Bitcoin to go up
to like 200K, rather than topping out at
at at 126. Like in 2017,
Bitcoin topped at around 20K, around
19,000,
and then we went into this start, you
know, this bear market, where we're
doing exactly what we're doing now, just
1/10 the price.
Um but because we had that euphoric
final rally, it led to alt season, and
it led to those final big rotations.
It led to a lot of retail coming in.
But we don't have retail coming in right
now, right? I mean, and unfortunately,
retail is still leaving, and you can
verify that just by looking at something
as simple as, you know, YouTube views to
these various crypto YouTube channels.
It's not what I want to happen. I mean,
I'd love it if my views could trend up,
but I mean, you can see that the views
to these different channels are are
dwindling. And what I really what I
think's happening is I think there's a
lot of people that are are kind of tired
of of
you know, a lot of the grift and and the
promises of the altcoin market and all
the rug pulls and stuff. And a lot of
people are just like, you know what?
They're not they're not concerned as
much anymore about missing the next meme
coin rally. They just don't care anymore
because they've done it enough times to
realize they're not going to make money
doing it. And so, people have just
become better investors, and and they
invest quiet, you know, in a more quiet
fashion. Maybe they invest in different
things, but they stop chasing things
that are there just to enrich the
founders. And so,
I mean, that's one of the main reasons
you see viewership trending down for a
lot of the different channels is
because,
you know, it it it
the gig is up in a sense, right? Like,
okay,
a lot of these projects need to start
actually producing something. It can't
just always be some promise of of
something that'll happen in the future.
It it needs to actually happen now, and
that's why I would argue that looking at
things that are actually making a profit
would be a good place to start. But, for
for Bitcoin now, I mean, you know, um my
guess is that the bear market as it has
been is going to be a very formidable
opponent here. Normally, we don't get
past it until later on. So, in the last
cycle, we didn't get through it in any
durable sense until January of the
post-halving year.
In the cycle before that, we didn't get
through it in any durable sense until
March of the post-halving year. In the
cycle before that, we didn't get through
it until June of the post-halving year.
And even then, we came back down. So,
you could argue we didn't really get get
cooking until August of 20 or sorry,
October of 2015. So, it's it's
historically taken, you know, into the
post-halving year to get back above it.
So, again, I would guess that Bitcoin
will will sort of find resistance at
these levels, you know, and and kind of
come back down in the August to
September time frame, and then we'll
figure out if we're going to put in that
market cycle bottom when we normally do.
Now, is it possible the bottom is in?
Obviously, it is, right? Like, I can't
sit here and pretend like it's
impossible for that to be the case.
But, if it is the case, it would
probably do, you know, it probably
wouldn't go anywhere because I think
there would still be a lot of people
fearful of a final drop in Q4
that would probably lead to a lot of
selling pressure continued throughout
the rest of the year. That would allow
Bitcoin to maybe not put in a new low,
but probably not really go that much
higher. Um
So, but that is my guess as to where we
are is that we're kind of just repeating
the structure over here. And so, what
would likely happen if we were to
continue what happened in 2018, is
Bitcoin would get rejected in like late
July, early August, come back down,
maybe bounce again, and then at some
point later on, you then figure out if
you're going to get that final drop or
not. But, that's my guess as to how this
is going to play out and and I think
um
you know, I think the volatility will
likely come back, but it's going to take
a little while, right? In terms of to
the upside in any terrible sense. And
normally, we wouldn't expect it in the
post having year anyways. And you know,
I know that feels like pretty far off,
but it's not really that far off in the
grand scheme of things.
We'll wrap it up there. Again, if you
guys like the content, make sure you
subscribe, give the video thumbs up. If
you want to meet potentially like-minded
people and be a bit more of um invest
from a more rational perspective rather
than chasing the hype, then again, I
would encourage you to go to the first
Investing Through the Cycles Conference,
ITC Conference,
taking place in Miami in November,
November 20th through the 22nd. Hope to
see you guys there.
We'll wrap it up. I'll see you guys next
time. Bye.